（上条(かみじょう)）
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)は―
The Croce di Pietro turned out to be a troublesome relic that could be activated regardless of the location or season.
場所も季節も関係なく使えるって
やっかいな代物だった
At this rate, Academy City will be conquered by the Roman Church at sunset.
このままじゃ 日没とともに―
学園都市が ローマ正教に
支配されちまうだって？
そんなことは 絶対にさせない！
I can't let them do that!
～♪
#13 Croce di Pietro
ハアッ！
（蹴る音）
（上条）ウワッ！
My, what a convenient place to put your head!
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
あら！　いい位置に頭が…
くそ…
Damn...
フフフッ…
辺りも暗くなってきたわ
It's starting to get dark.
Isn't it about time for you to go home?
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
ねえ
そろそろ お家(うち)に帰る時間かな？
Or do you want to spend a stimulating night with me?
それとも おねえさんと ちょっぴり
刺激的な夜を過ごしてみる？
One more...
あとひとつ…
I just need one more edge in this fight.
あとひとつ 何かがあれば…
あとひとつ…
One more!
Its name is fire.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
その名は炎　その役は剣(つるぎ)
Its form is that of a sword.
Appear. Devour my body to gain strength.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
顕現せよ！
我が身を食らいて力となせ！
Innocentius!
魔女狩りの王(イノケンティウス)！
Let's go, Innocentius!
いくぞ 魔女狩りの王(イノケンティウス)
Fortis931...
Fortis(フォルティス)931
Prove to them why my name is the strongest!
我が名が最強である理由を
ここに証明しろ！
（上条）ハッ…
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）一緒に死ね！
Die, both of you!
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）ハッ…
（上条）危ねえだろう バカ！
You idiot!
あっ しまった！
Crap—
Ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
灰は灰に　塵(ちり)は塵に！
Vampire killer, crimson cross!
吸血殺しの紅十字！
Go home, you lame magician!
（上条）
家に帰れ！　ヘタレ魔術師！
黙れ ド素人！
Shut up, you amateur!
ウワッ！
Innocentius!
魔女狩りの王(イノケンティウス)！
Get out of the way!
（上条）ジャマだ バカ！
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）君こそ どけ！
No, you get out of the way!
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
どういうこと？
これじゃ 動きが読めない
What is this?
I can't tell how they're moving like this...
（２人）
ハアッ！
A basis.
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
基準点… 絶対の基準点が欲しい
I need an absolute basis.
Clear rules.
明確なルールを…
So that no one else will suffer misfortune because of differences in values.
皆が幸せになって もう誰も―
価値観の齟齬(そご)が生みだす悲劇に
巻き込まれないような―
A perfect world...
そんな最高の世界を
That's why I have to win.
だから 勝つのよ
勝って 答えを作ってみせる
I'll win and reach an answer.
I am...
私は… 私の名は Basis(バスイス)104
My name is Basis104.
ハッ… 伏せろ 素人！
Get down, amateur!
Stiyl!
ステイル！
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）どこへ行くの？
（上条）ハッ…
Where are you going?
Your opponent is over here.
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
坊やの相手は こちらでしょう？
（上条）
いいかげんにしろよ
何人傷つければ気が済むんだ？
That's enough, already.
How many people do you have to hurt?
フフッ… おねえさんだって
誰も傷つけたくないわ
I don't want to hurt anyone, you know.
But I have an objective.
でも 私には目的があるの
Now, come.
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
さあ　来なさい
If I crush you, my mission's complete.
坊やをつぶせば
それで おねえさんの役目は終わり
The Croce di Pietro and Roman Church will make the perfect world for me.
あとは 使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)が…
ローマ正教が―
おねえさんの望んでいる世界を
作ってくれる
What kind of objective is that?
（上条）
なにが目的だ
Stop talking so arrogantly when you're just watching others do the work for you.
他人任せで
未来を決めてもらってるぶんざいで
偉そうな口利いてんじゃねえ
Do the work for me, huh...
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
他人任せ …か
Yeah. I don't really care who it is.
そう
おねえさんはね 誰だっていいのよ
Someone just has to group up the various principles and ideas of the world.
誰かが
この世界に転がる主義主張を―
束ねてさえくれればね
And I'm going to protect that basis no matter what.
そして おねえさんは
その基準点を絶対に守る
So that's your objective.
（上条）
それが お前の目的か
I don't really get those kind of complicated arguments.
俺には
小難しいことなんか分からねえ
But I can't just give into such a stupid request like handing over Academy City and everyone in it.
だけど そんな目的のために
学園都市のみんなを―
差し出せなんていうバカな申し出は
受け入れられない
You can say that because you don't know, boy.
坊やは知らないから
そういう口が利けるのよ
You've never seen someone just stand there in shock at what is occurring in front of her.
身に降りかかる事態に対して
呆然(ぼうぜん)と立ち尽くすしかない―
あの表情を見たことがないから
You've never heard someone simply say, "It hurts."
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）
ただ“悔しい”という
ひと言を聞いたことがないから
Even then, that's no reason to attack Academy City.
（上条）
だとしても それが 学園都市を―
好きに攻撃していいなんて
理由にはならない
That doesn't justify using someone as a stepping stone for someone else's sake!
誰かのために 別の誰かを
踏み台にしていいなんて理屈には
すり替えられない！
No matter what!
（上条）絶対にだ！
（ｵﾘｱﾅ）ンッ…
The issues you're having are things that everyone feels.
お前が抱えてる問題なんて
みんな 感じていることなんだよ
Everyone fails, and sometimes they fall.
誰だって失敗するし 時には転ぶ
But if you fall, you can just stand back up!
けどな 転んだら起き上がればいい
Even if you look miserable, even if everything doesn't go as planned, you have to stand up!
どれだけ ぶざまでも
全部 裏目に出たとしても―
立ち上がるんだよ！
Don't just throw away someone else's life!
他人の人生を てめえが
途中で投げ出すんじゃねえ！
Which will you choose, Oriana Thomson?
お前は どちらを選ぶ？
オリアナ＝トムソン
Just because you failed once, are you going to let others do things for you?
１回 失敗したからって
全てを他人に任せておくのか？
If they failed, are you going to lend those failures a hand?
たとえ 失敗しても―
その失敗した人たちに もう一度
手を差し伸べてみるのか？
ハァ…
I'm ending this.
これで決着をつける
I state this to all of the abilities in my body:
我が身に宿る全ての才能に告げる
Unleash your full potential, and destroy the target in front of you!
その全霊を解放し
目の前の敵を討て！
Damn it...
ちくしょう…
（吹寄(ふきよせ)）
まったく…
Sheesh!
Can't you put even a little effort into making this festival a success?
少しは大会を成功させようという
努力はできないの？　貴様は
I have a bit of a problem.
（姫神(ひめがみ)）
ちょっと困ったことがあって　来て
Come.
Don't expect anything.
期待はするな
僕にとっても専門外なんだ
This is beyond my expertise.
Go, Kami-yan.
（土御門(つちみかど)）
行け　カミやん
Everyone...
みんな…
They were all trying to protect the present.
今を守ろうとしていた
I'll be back at your hospital room before the Night Parade starts.
ナイトパレードが始まるまでに
お前の病室に帰る
So wait for me, no matter what!
だから 必ず待っててくれ
That was the mark of my determination.
あれが 俺の覚悟の現れだ
And I'm just going to let that all go to waste?
それをこんなところで
台なしにしてたまるかよ！
Like hell!
（上条）
ステイル！
Stiyl!
Don't worry about me, go for the Croce di Pietro.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
僕はいい　それよりも 使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)だ
オリアナに場所を吐かせろ
あの霊装の発動を食い止めて…
Make Oriana reveal where it is.
Stop it from activating...
You need not worry.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
心配する必要はないかと
もうすぐ全てが終わりますので
Everything will end soon.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
リドヴィア＝ロレンツェッティ
Lidvia Lorenzetti...
The Croce di Pietro will soon activate, and Academy City will be put under the Roman Catholic Church's control.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
まもなく
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)は その効果を発動し―
学園都市は我々ローマ正教のもとに
改変されます
俺たちみたいなジャマ者は
みんな ここで排除するってのか？
Are you going to just get rid of people like us who get in the way?
We grieve over your wounds and wish to heal them as well.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
我々は そちらのキズをも慈しみ
治してみせると告げているだけで
もちろん それが―
Of course, only if we can determine that doing so will profit the Roman Church.
ローマ正教にとって有益だと
判断できればですが
なんだと？
What?!
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
まともに取り合うな 上条当麻(とうま)
Don't argue with her, Kamijou Touma.
リドヴィアは
この近くにいるはずだ
Lidvia should be close by.
The cross, too...
霊装も そこに…
I should clarify.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
誤解なきよう告げておきますが
The Croce di Pietro is not in Academy City at the moment.
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)は
現在 学園都市にはありませんので
なに？
What?
At its peak, the area of Roman Catholic Church revival affected by the Croce di Pietro was 47,000 square kilometers.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)によって作り出された―
ローマ教皇領は 最盛期には
４万7,000平方キロメートル
学園都市の外から放ったとしても
余裕で街の全域をカバーできるかと
It's safe to assume that it'll easily cover the entirety of Academy City even if it's activated outside.
ンッ… やられた　オリアナは囮(おとり)か
They got us...
Oriana was just a decoy.
It's unfortunate that she was defeated, but the Croce di Pietro will turn even that into a beneficial situation.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
彼女が撃破されてしまったのは
残念ですが
それすらも 使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)が―
都合のよい方向へ
改変してくれるでしょう
The only point that is of concern to us now is that science will bow to religion.
こちらにとって重要なのは
科学が宗教に屈するという一点のみ
科学を否定し
我々の力を示すことで―
By denying science and showing our power, we will show the power of the Lord.
主の権威は取り戻せるかと
Searching and attacking...
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
探索に攻撃… 今の土御門に
２回も魔術を使うのはムリだ
Tsuchimikado can't use magic twice in that state.
Damn it!
くそ！
じゃ どうすりゃいいんだよ？
What should I do then?!
We will not destroy Academy City.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
我々は
学園都市の破壊は行いません
科学という異教を捨てさせたのち
あなたたちを愛すべき同胞として…
Once we make you throw away the cult of science, we will embrace you as loving comrades.
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）
君は土御門を呼べ
Call Tsuchimikado
占術円陣で
リドヴィアの居場所を割り出し
and have him use his search magic to calculate Lidvia's location.
僕の通信術式を使って
外の部隊に任せれば…
If I use my communication spell, we can leave it to the forces outside.
It's useless.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
ムダですので
The Croce di Pietro will change the world in...
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)によって
世界が改変されるまで…
107 seconds.
残り107秒
Checkmate!
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
チェックメートです
（ｽﾃｲﾙ）ンッ…
（上条）何かないのか？
Is there no other way?
この状況を
ひっくり返す最後の切り札が
Some trump card to turn this situation around?
夜空に浮かぶ星座を利用した魔術…
A spell used by the constellations in the night sky...
星の光を地上で集めて…
Gathering starlight on the ground...
土御門！
Tsuchimikado!
How many points outside of Academy City are there that can cover all of Academy City?!
学園都市の外にあって
学園都市全体を巻き込む―
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)の使用ポイントは
いくつある？
What?
（土御門）なんだって？
（上条）黙って答えろ！
Shut up and answer me!
今の条件で
いちばん遠いポイントは どこだ？
Where's the furthest point matching those criteria?
The northern perimeter of Academy City.
（土御門）
学園都市外周北部
1,700メートルってとこだにゃ
About 1700 meters out.
What about it?
それが どうしたんだ？
Daihaseisai Schedule
20 more seconds...
あと20秒…
It's the end.
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
もう おしまいです
You're right, it's the end.
（上条）
確かに もう おしまいだな
結果が このザマってんじゃ
俺は確かに おしまいだよ
If this is the end, then it's over for me.
（上条）
なあ　そう思うだろう リドヴィア
Hey, don't you think so Lidvia?
Even if I destroyed your illusion, I couldn't even keep the promise I made with my classmate.
いくら てめえの幻想を
ぶち殺せたっつってもよ
クラスメートとの約束も
守れないようじゃな
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
はぁ？　何を…
What are you—
Wh-Wha—
The current time is exactly 6:30pm.
現在時刻は 午後６時30分ジャスト
In case you didn't know...
知らなかったか？
ナイトパレードが始まる時間だ
That's when the Night Parade starts.
この光量があれば
星空を十分に塗りつぶせる
With this much light, the stars can be blotted out easily.
（上条）
お前が どこにいようとな
No matter where you are...
You lost to the light that everyone protecting the Daihaseisai created.
（上条）
お前は 大覇星(だいはせい)祭を守る―
みんなが作った光に負けたんだ
You should have figured out who the main character of the Daihaseisai is.
大覇星祭の主役が誰なのか
調べておくべきだったな
What now?
どうする？
俺は お前が使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)を壊して―
Personally I think you should destroy the Croce di Pietro and promise not to bother Academy City anymore.
もう学園都市に
ちょっかい出さないっていうなら
それでいいと思ってるけど
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
本気で言ってるので？
Are you serious?
私が敬虔(けいけん)なるローマ正教徒の
ひとりだとお忘れかと
You must have forgotten that I am a devout member of the Roman Catholic Church.
Oh really?
（上条）
そうかい
だったら 運動会らしく
追いかけっこでもするんだな
Then I guess you're going to be running around in a game of tag, just like a sports festival...
Lidvia Lorenzetti.
リドヴィア＝ロレンツェッティ
So...
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
それで 当麻は
私には ひと言も言わずに―
You engaged in a battle that may have determined the fate of Academy City and the world without letting me know,
世界と学園都市の命運を懸けた
魔術戦に参加したあげく―
ボコボコにされて 病院に
運ばれてきたっていうわけなんだね
and on top of that, you got hospitalized after getting beaten up by a mage.
けど インデックスさんってば
魔術と聞いたら―
But Index-san, whenever I mention magic you always come stumbling right into the middle of it.
事件の中心点に
トテトテ歩いてくるから
ンンッ… 当麻！
Touma, that makes it sound like I'm really stupid!
それじゃ とっても
私がバカみたいに聞こえるんだよ
ププッ！
自分で気づいていない時点で―
The fact that you never noticed shows that you're a real—
お前は本物の… ハッ…
My my, what a delightful scene.
（黒子(くろこ)）
あらあら
これは また愉快な場面ですこと
今 真面目なところなんだから
チャチャ入れないでよ 短髪！
We're having a serious talk here, so get out, short hair.
（美琴(みこと)）黒子
（黒子）ハッ…
Kuroko.
（美琴）
風紀委員(ジャッジメント)の治安維持活動って―
Ordinary citizens are allowed to cooperate in Judgment's peacekeeping, right?
民間人が
協力してもいいんだったわよね？
お姉様
さすがに病院内では ちょっと…
Onee-sama, you do realize this is a hospital...
くそ！　まあいいわ
Damn.
Well whatever.
今日の最終結果 見た？
ウチの学校は あんたの学校なんて
Did you see today's final results?
Our school sailed right past yours into first place!
軽～く抜いて
トップに立ってんだからね
罰ゲームのこと
忘れてんじゃないわよ
I hope you haven't forgotten about our agreement.
い… いや 罰ゲームって言われても
この体じゃ 競技に参加できないし
B-But I can't do anything like that with my body in this condition...
ふ～ん… じゃ…
Then...
Be prepared to die.
（美琴）死ぬ気でやれば？
（上条）えっ…
ああ　なんて かわいそうな
オリアナ＝トムソン　フフフッ…
Poor Oriana Thompson.
救わなければ
I must save her.
あそこに捕らえられたる
迷える罪人(つみびと)をこの手で…
And all those poor lost sinners.
（ﾛｰﾗ）
アー アー
アテンション プリーズ
Ahem, attention please!
イギリス清教 アークビショップ
ローラ＝スチュアート
This is the Archbishop of the Church of England, Laura Stewart.
…て 名乗れば分からずなんて
And now that I've introduced myself, you can't ignore me. Right, Milady Lidvia?
冷たきことは言わぬでしょうね？
リドヴィアお嬢ちゃん
なぜ この自家用機が？
How did you find me in this private jet?
（ﾛｰﾗ）
フフフッ…
羽田(はねだ)に止まりし機体の壁に―
I had them slap a little present onto the wall of your plane at Haneda.
ペタリと貼らせていただきました
相変わらず気味の悪しことね
You're quite creepy, as always.
That personality of yours where you laugh harder the more you're pressured...
追い詰められれば
追い詰められるほどに―
ケタケタ笑いし その性格
どうにかならぬものなのかしら？
Isn't there anything you can do about that?
困難な局面ほど 打開したときの
喜びは大きくなるものですから
The harsher the pain, the sweeter the joy will be upon overcoming it.
私は主に感謝しなければなりません
I must give thanks to the Lord.
（ﾛｰﾗ）フフフッ…
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）何か？
What?
（ﾛｰﾗ）
壁が高ければ高いほど―
The taller a wall is, the greater the satisfaction upon getting over it, huh...
それを越えた瞬間の喜びが
大きくなりける …か
There is some truth in what you say...
確かに それも一理あるなと
思うただけよ この断崖絶壁野郎
you little animal at the edge of a cliff!
（ﾛｰﾗ）
フフッ… リドヴィア
ローマの教えを捨て去りて―
Lidvia, I don't mind saving you if you give up on Rome's teachings and lick my feet.
我が足元をなめれば
救いてやりてもよいのだけどね
What nonsense are you talking about?
何をたわけたことを…
I see...
（ﾛｰﾗ）
そうか　なれば あれと一緒に
クレーターでも作りていろ
Then maybe you and that thing can make a crater.
The Croce di Pietro!
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）
使徒十字(クローチェディピエトロ)…
I won't allow that to happen!
させませんので！
At this speed of descent I should make it...
今の速度ならば間に合う
いえ 間に合わせてみせますので
No, I definitely will make it!
時間はギリギリですが
だからこそ 面白い
I have no time...
but that's what makes it fun!
（ﾘﾄﾞｳﾞｨｱ）ハッ…
（ﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄ）ウワーッ！
Now then, Lidvia...
（ﾛｰﾏ）
さて リドヴィア
貴様は どちらを選ぶ？
Which will you pick?
世界最大級の霊装か
迷える哀れな子羊か
The most powerful spiritual tool in the world,
or the lost and pitiful servant?
（ﾛｰﾗ）
困難は大きければ大きいほど
それを乗り越えたとき―
The greater the challenge,
the greater the satisfaction once you trample over me, the creator of the challenge, right?
それを作り出した私を
踏みにじる喜びが大きくなるのよね
I will trample...
踏みにじる？
over that unreachable flower...
あの高い鼻を思う存分…
as much as I want!
（ｱﾚｲｽﾀｰ）
随分と
大きく揺らいでしまったものだな
That was quite the tremor.
カギとなる幻想殺し(イマジンブレイカー)の成長は
いまだに不安定
The development of the key, Imagine Breaker, is still unstable.
これも 果たして使えるかどうか
Will I be able to use this?
私自身が打って出る可能性も
考えねばならないのかもしれんな
I may have to consider the possibility of taking action myself.
えっ？　ここで何をしてるの？
What are you doing here?
I was sleeping on the bench in the waiting room,
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
待合室のベンチで寝てたんだけど
but they told me I can't use it in the morning...
朝になったら使っちゃダメって
言われたから
ふかふかベッド…
This bed is so nice and soft...
Are you okay now?
もう大丈夫なの？
Yes...
うん
カエルのお医者さんが言うには―
The frog doctor said I can leave tomorrow or the day after.
明日か あさってには
退院できるって
You look kind of sad, Aisa...
秋沙(あいさ) なんか寂しそうに見えるけど
なんで？
Why?
あの人は やっぱり
今回もムチャなことをやってたの？
Did he go do something reckless again?
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
うん　そうだよ
Yeah, he did.
Oh right, I haven't heard all the details yet,
そうそう　詳しい話は
まだ聞いてないんだけど
なんか
大覇星祭とかいうのを利用して
but apparently the Roman Catholic magicians tried to take advantage of the Daihaseisai to attack.
ローマ正教の魔術師たちが
攻めてきたんだって
And so, without saying a single word to me,
それで 当麻は また―
私には何の相談もしないで
１人で突っ走って
he went on a huge rampage and only told me about it like he was making a report after it all happened!
１人で大暴走してきた次第とか
事後報告気味に言われたんだよ
ンンッ… 許せないよね
Unacceptable!
そっか　誰でもよかったんじゃ…
I see...
It doesn't matter who it is...
あの人は
困ってる人なら 誰でも助ける
He'll help out anyone in need...
Not just me.
私じゃなくても
私は 本当は―
Maybe I shouldn't have been saved...
助けてもらうべきじゃ
なかったんじゃ…
私は みんなの迷惑にしか
なっていないのかもしれないね
It looks like all I do is cause trouble for everyone.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）そんなわけないじゃん
（姫神）えっ？
Of course not.
だって 当麻は秋沙と一緒にいると
楽しそうだもん
Touma seems to enjoy spending time with you, after all.
（上条）
つうか 吹寄さ
Hold on, Fukiyose-san!
人の病室 訪ねて来て
ビンタを浴びせるってのは―
What kind hospital visit is this, suddenly slapping me like that?
どういうことなんだっつうの
（吹寄）
黙りなさい！
Be quiet!
いきなり 男の裸なんか見たら
誰だって驚くわよ
Anyone would be surprised seeing a naked boy!
（上条）
着替えてる最中に入ってきたのは
そっちだろう
You're the one who barged in while I was in the middle of changing!
（吹寄）
なんですって？
What was that?!
（姫神）
ねえ　あの人が なんで戦うのか
あなたには分かる？
Hey...
Why does he fight?
Do you know?
I wonder.
（ｲﾝﾃﾞｯｸｽ）
さあ？　前に聞いたときは
自分のためだとか言ってたけど
When I asked him, he said it was for his own sake.
Maybe that's what happiness is for Touma.
当麻にとっては それが
幸せなんじゃない？　ヘヘッ…
～♪
For better or for worse, Index and I suddenly find ourselves headed for Italy.
Next Episode
（上条）
幸か不幸か 俺とインデックスは
突然 イタリアへ
I guess we might as well relax and look at the sights!
こうなったら
のんびり観光と しゃれ込むぜ！
Wait, is that Orsola?
…て オルソラ？　天草(あまくさ)式の？
The Amakusa Church too?
Next episode: "City of Water."
次回 「水の都」
When science and magic cross paths, this epic will begin!
科学と魔術が交差するとき
物語は始まる